

# Julien Full Stack Web Developer

Location	Phone	Web	Email
Castres, France	+33 6 52 72 03 55	julienmonty.com	julien.monty@gmail.com

# **INTRODUCTION** Who am I.

I'm 31 and I'm a full-stack web developer based in France (Tarn, Castres). I'm specialized in Laravel PHP framework (for the back-end) and Vue.js Javascript framework (for the front-end).

My passion for web development pushes me to give the best of myself for each project, and to improve my knowledge in the field of web technologies keeping me regularly informed of the latest innovations.

Since I was young, I'm interested in computers, and more generally in technologies. At 16, I started to learn web development, which has quickly grown into a passion. That's why I decided to make it my full time job after working several years for IT companies.

# **EXPERTISE**

Domains of my expertise.



# FRONT-END

I develop clear, fast and easy-to-use interfaces. My favorite frameworks are Vue.js for Javascript and Bootstrap for CSS.



# **BACK-END**

I develop PHP applications using the MVC architecture in order to optimize their performance and maintainability. My favorite PHP framework is Laravel.



#### **GRAPHISME**

I design for the web and for the print (flyer, logo, business card, ...). I mainly use Adobe softwares (Photoshop, Illustrator, XD).



# **SERVEUR**

I install, configure and maintain Linux (Debian) web servers. I use virtualization for my development environments (Docker, Vagrant, VMWare).

# **LANGUAGES**

My favorites languages.

85% HTML

**70% JAVASCRIPT** 

80 % CSS

75% PHP

70 % SQL

65 % UI/UX

I also have some experience in the following languages: Ruby, Python, LaTeX.

# **TOOLS**

My favorites tools.

80% VUE.JS 85 % LARAVEL

**70% WORDPRESS** 80 % GIT

75 % OS (WINDOWS, OSX, LINUX) 65 % WEBPACK

80% PHOTOSHOP **70% ILLUSTRATOR** 

I also have some experience with the following tools: JQuery, Prestashop, AngularJS, Ruby On Rails, Virtualisation (Vagrant, Docker, VMWare), Amazon AWS, Visual Studio Code, Atom, Premiere Pro, After Effects.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

My professional career.

2016 - Present

**BEPROJECT**Full Stack Web Developer & Graphist

Mazamet, France

Development, deployment and maintenance of business web applications for pharmaceutical and automotive big companies. Team leader of a 4-5 web developers team. Installation, configuration and maintenance of server infrastructures for the web.

2015 - 2017

FREELANCE - UNPIXEL Full Stack Web Developer & Graphist

Castres, France

Development (functional and graphic mock-up, integration, deployment, maintenance) of custom-made website or CMS for small and medium companies. Graphic creations for logos, flyers, business cards, ...

2012 - 2014DEVOTEAM

IT Technician
Castres, France

IT support for Pierre Fabre company.

2011 - 2012

ACCENTURE IT Technician

Dublin, Irlande

IT support for Freeport company.

**2010 - 2011** 

**HEWLETT-PACKARD** IT Coach

Rabat, Maroc

3 months mission abroad to train IT technicians on their location.

2010 - 2011

HEWLETT-PACKARD

IT Technician

Dublin, Irlande

IT Support / Coaching for Total company.

**EDUCATION** 

My school cursus.

2008

**CATHOLIC INSTITUTE**Law degree (not validated)

Toulouse, France

First year of law degree validated at the Catholic Institute of Toulouse.

· ·

**2006** 

HIGH SCHOOL PIERRE D'ARAGON Scientific Baccalaureate

Muret, France

Scientific BAC option Physics-Chemistry validated with honors.

**LANGUES** 

The languages I speak.

99% FRENCH

85 % ENGLISH

**HOBBIES** 

How I spend my free time.

TENNIS

I've been playing tennis in competition for 15 years and I taught tennis for 5 years to child from 5 to 17 years old.

\*

TRAIL - HIKING

I practice trail in competition and I like to hike in nature.

PHOTOGRAPHY

I've been practicing photography for a few years. I like animal, landscape and macro photography.

VIDEO GAMES

I've been playing video games since I was a child and still today when I have some free time left.